Title: Classification of civil unrest relevant tweets in the Mexico region

***************************************
Background
***************************************

Event analysis of the form considered here is an established concept in social science research. Civil
unrest is a large concept intended to capture the myriad ways in which people express their protest against
things that aﬀect their lives and for which they assume that the government (local, regional or national) has
a responsibility (e.g., cost of urban transportation, poor infrastructure, etc.). If the action is directed against
private actors, there is normally a connection to government policy or behavior, e.g., a labor strike against a
private company can disrupt the rhythm of everyday life for the rest of society, turn violent or lead to a series
of disruptive strikes which require government involvement, and thus responsibility in the eyes of citizens.
Civil unrest does not include acts by criminals for purely private gain. While authoritarian governments
may outlaw civil protest and thus ‘criminalize’ the participants, social scientists would distinguish illegal
political protests from illegal criminal activities. Gang members stopping public buses to extort payoﬀs from
bus owners would not be a civil unrest event, though people protesting afterward against the government’s
inability to control such gangs would be considered civil unrest.

This expansive deﬁnition of civil unrest means that one can ﬁnd it everywhere, including European
protests against austerity or marches against an oil pipeline from Canada across the US to the Gulf of
Mexico. Latin America, nevertheless, offers some special characteristics that make it an excellent region
for study in our project. The region experiences a plethora of civil unrest events every day (providing a
sufficient number of GSR events to train machine learning models), is well covered by international and
national news media (facilitating the task of generating ground truth), is the object of detailed empirical
research and polling (permitting the description of the social, political and economic context within which
civil unrest occurs) and has a signiﬁcant and growing number of social network users (thus supporting the
use of modern data mining algorithms).

Read the article "Beating the news with EMBERS- Forecasting Civil Unrest using Open Source Indicator.pdf" for more details

***************************************
Requirements
***************************************

You are allowed to use the following tweets in Spanish or any public data to train a classification model 
that is able classify new tweets as relevant or irrelevant to civil unrest. You can use JAVA or PYTHON. 

1. train_posi_tweets_2007.txt
4000 positive tweets 

2. train_nega_tweets_2007.txt
8000 negative tweets

3. unlabeled_tweetss_2007.txt
51647 unlabeled tweets 
(note: these unlabeled tweets are provided in case you want to try some unsupervised techniques (e.g., clustering) to generate your classifier). 

***************************************
Tweet Format
***************************************
tweet = {"lang": "es", "city": "Puebla", "embersId": "90ec51abad3f32705b511f5d0cd58b49d11ac40c", "uid": 152810236, "Parent_embersId": "7f208b7f82b8f29ad2349779e774f419f2915ea4", "derivedFrom": "1e1d43c10095a980e0746ace31e4f946", "instantloc": {"city": [["heroica puebla de zaragoza", [-98.22, 19.05], 1467419]], "state": []}, "key_count": 2, "score": 0.0013994149053899736, "text": "\u201c@mlucascir: RT \u201c@mauolmedo: La marcha anti pe\u00f1a en #Puebla  M\u00e9xico http://t.co/CXRjG59d\u201d...buena marcha gente de Puebla.", "date": "2012-07-22 20:30:23", "country": "Mexico", "text_items": [["rt", "march", "gent", "pen", "anti", "puebl", "mexic"], ["#puebla"], ["@mlucascir", "@mauolmedo"], ["http://t.co/cxrjg59d\u201d...buena"]], "screen_name": "DUEMIKE"}

The above is an example tweet. The following are the basic items
tweet['embersId'] gives the tweet id. 
tweet['text'] gives the tweet text.
tweet['text_items'][0] provides the list of stemmed terms of the tweet text. 
tweet['text_items'][1] provides the list of hashtags in the text. 
tweet['text_items'][2] provides the list of user mentions in the text. 
tweet['text_items'][3] provides the list of links in the text. 


***************************************
Submission Format and Deadline
***************************************
You need to submit two python files:
1. Submit your python or java code that you used to generate you classifier baed on the training data. 
1. Submit your python or java code that will read tweets from the test file ("test_tweets.txt") in the same folder
and generate a dictionary json file ("predictions.txt") with classification results of all the testing tweets in "test_tweets.txt". The key 
in the dictionary object is "Embers_id", and the value is the classification (True or False). 

See "test_tweets.txt" and "predictions.txt" for example. Note that, the posted file "test_tweets.txt" does not have the actual testing tweets that we will use to grade your model. You need to ensure that, when we run your program, “test_tweets.txt” is loaded and the results of the predictions are written to “predictions.txt”. If you have questions, please do let us know. 

The deadline is May 8 (Sunday) Mid-night 


***************************************
Confidential disclosure requirement 
***************************************

The tweets are only used for this challenge and NOT ALLOWED to be used or shared for any other purposes.


***************************************
Plagiarism Policy
***************************************

Cheating in this challenge will result in an E grade for the course. You are allowed to use all my code shared within the class and to use any publically avaiable code. 
However, you are not allowed to copy code from the other class mates. 